So we've gone through the dos and don'ts of giving a presentation.
所以我们已经完成了演示文稿的注意事项。
The last point I shared thing you should do is to engage the audience at the beginning with a hook.
我分享的最后一点你应该做的是在开始时用钩子吸引观众。
Why am I doing this with my finger.
为什么我用我的手指做这个。
Because this is a hook.
因为这是一个钩子。
This is a hook this shape.
这是一个钩这个形状。
We use it when we go fishing.
我们去钓鱼的时候会用到它。
We use it when we hang up our clothes.
我们挂衣服的时候会用到它。
We can imagine grabbing the audience with that right at the beginning and making them focus on us.
我们可以想象一开始就抓住观众，让他们专注于我们。
We use a hook to attract the attention of the audience at the beginning of a presentation.
我们在演示开始时使用钩子来吸引观众的注意力。
Pretty simple.
很简单。
But how do we do that.
但是我们如何做到这一点。
What kind of hooks are there.
有什么样的钩子。
Well there are many but I want to talk about three and these three are very easy to do.
嗯，有很多，但我想谈谈三个，这三个很容易做到。
Very easy.
很容易。
And I will teach you how to do them now.
我现在就教你怎么做。
OK.
好的。
Start with a rhetorical question.
从一个反问开始。
What is a rhetorical question.
什么是反问句。
A rhetorical question is a question that doesn't need to be answered.
修辞问题是不需要回答的问题。
Doesn't need to be answered.
不需要回答。
That's a rhetorical question.
这是一个反问。
Why would we use a rhetorical question.
我们为什么要使用反问。
I see that's a rhetorical question I asked.
我看到这是我问的一个反问。
Did you watching this go Oh I know.
你看过这个吗 哦，我知道。
No you didn't.
不，你没有。
But you might have been thinking about the answer.
但你可能一直在思考答案。
That is why we use rhetorical questions.
这就是我们使用反问句的原因。
Have you ever wondered why people use rhetorical questions.
你有没有想过为什么人们使用反问句。
There is another a rhetorical question gets the audience to start thinking about the topic.
还有一个反问让观众开始思考这个话题。
It's a great way to start a presentation.
这是开始演示的好方法。
And one really really simple honestly very simple beginning that you can use for pretty much any topic
一个非常非常简单，非常简单的开始，您可以将其用于几乎任何主题
is to start with.
是开始。
Have you ever.
你有没有。
Have you ever wondered.
你有没有想过。
And then you can say something about your topic.
然后你可以谈谈你的话题。
That's a pretty generic one.
这是一个很笼统的。
Pretty generic but it works.
非常通用，但它有效。
Have you ever wondered.
你有没有想过。
Let's say my topic is about Mars.
假设我的主题是关于火星的。
Have you ever wondered what it would would be like to live on Mars.
你有没有想过住在火星上会是什么样子。
Ever wondered what it would be like to live on Mars.
曾经想过住在火星上会是什么样子。
Nobody in the audience needs to say oh yes yes yes.
观众中没有人需要说哦，是的，是的。
I've wondered.
我想知道。
Hello.
你好。
Meet me.
跟我碰面。
Can I answer.
我能回答吗。
No.
不。
It's to get the audience to start thinking OK.
这是为了让观众开始思考OK。
So that is one way to begin a presentation and we can do a couple others we could say have.
所以这是开始演示的一种方式，我们可以做一些其他我们可以说有的方法。
Have you ever wished Have you ever wished you could live 500 years.
你有没有想过你有没有希望你能活 500 岁。
Whatever the topic is it's not so important what the question is.
无论主题是什么，问题是什么都不是那么重要。
It's got to be pretty open.
它必须非常开放。
Generally make people think.
一般会让人思考。
But you can use Have you ever wished.
但是你可以使用你有没有想过。
Have you ever wondered you'd say what's the most what's the most important thing.
你有没有想过你会说什么是最重要的。
You know that nobody taught you what's the most important thing that you know or the most important
你知道没有人教你什么是你知道的最重要的事情或最重要的事情
thing you know that nobody taught you.
你知道没有人教你的事情。
Now again you don't have to answer that because you're in a room maybe full of people.
现在你不必再回答这个问题了，因为你在一个房间里可能挤满了人。
If that's an interview that maybe you have to answer it maybe it's not rhetorical but you don't have
如果那是一个采访，也许你必须回答它，也许这不是修辞，但你没有
to go like this.
像这样去。
You should just be thinking about it.
你应该只是考虑一下。
And it's very effective.
而且非常有效。
I'm making you consider this topic.
我我让你考虑这个话题。
Now I'm going to start talking about maybe something profound that I've learned through my life experience
现在我要开始谈论一些我从生活经历中学到的深刻的东西
deep and meaningful.
深刻而有意义。
Maybe I'm going to talk about how our experiences teach us profound and meaningful things.
也许我要谈谈我们的经历如何教会我们深刻而有意义的事情。
So this is one type.
所以这是一种。
This is one type of hook.
这是一种钩子。
Let's go on to the next.
让我们继续下一个。
OK.
好的。
The next type of hook is what I call making it personal.
下一种类型的钩子就是我所说的个性化。
There's something about humanity called empathy.
人类有一种东西叫做同理心。
And this is a kind of ability to feel how others feel especially for those who we have some real personal
这是一种感受他人感受的能力，特别是对于那些我们有一些真正私人的人
connection with.
与连接。
For those who we actually meet face to face to be honest if you hear about something terrible happening
老实说，如果您听说发生了可怕的事情，那么对于我们真正面对面的人
to somebody you've never met or know nothing about.
给你从未见过或一无所知的人。
You probably think well that's sad but it might not completely ruin your day.
你可能认为这很可悲，但它可能不会完全毁掉你的一天。
But when you hear about something bad that's happened to somebody you've met before you will naturally
但是当你听到之前遇到的人发生了不好的事情时，你自然会
probably go and can't believe that happened.
可能去，不敢相信发生了。
And it might ruin your day.
它可能会毁了你的一天。
What's the difference.
有什么不同。
Well there's a connection there.
嗯，那里有联系。
There's a natural empathy that comes out more strongly when we see people face to face when we actually
当我们真正面对面地看到人们时，自然会产生更强烈的同理心
know people.
认识人。
We have a real connection with them.
我们与他们有着真正的联系。
So if there's a person there in front of me giving a presentation I naturally want to be connected with
因此，如果有人在我面前进行演示，我自然想与之建立联系
them.
他们。
And the more they talk about themselves maybe the more empathy I will have with them.
他们谈论自己的次数越多，我对他们的同情可能就越多。
If they tell me why they care about a topic it's almost like they're taking me with them because I'm
如果他们告诉我他们为什么关心一个话题，那几乎就像他们带我去一样，因为我是
interested in them right.
对他们感兴趣吧。
Because of empathy and they explain why they're interested in this topic.
因为同理心，他们解释了为什么他们对这个话题感兴趣。
Now I'm interested in the topic kind of through them.
现在我通过他们对这个话题感兴趣。
It's a weird thing but if you watch a lot of presentations especially good presentations you'll see
这是一件很奇怪的事情，但是如果您观看很多演示文稿，尤其是好的演示文稿，您会看到
that you'll see the person the presenter first share a little story a tiny little story to explain a
你会看到演示者首先分享一个小故事一个小故事来解释一个
little bit of background o you NDE to talk a little bit about why they care about that thing maybe or
一点点背景，你 NDE 来谈谈他们为什么关心那件事，也许或者
talk about how they first got interested in that.
谈谈他们最初是如何对此产生兴趣的。
Why are they're passionate about this topic that they're sharing.
他们为什么对他们正在分享的这个话题充满热情。
Basically basically here are some ways we can do that.
基本上基本上这里有一些我们可以做到这一点的方法。
Well when I was about 7 when I was about 7 OK.
好吧，当我大约 7 岁时，我大约 7 岁。
And maybe we're talking about maybe my presentation is about Mars like I said before when I was about
也许我们在谈论也许我的演讲是关于火星的，就像我之前说的那样
7 my father took me outside and I saw that he had brought a telescope home.
7 我父亲带我出去，我看到他带了一个望远镜回家。
Wow.
哇。
A telescope a telescope is something you use to see far away.
望远镜 望远镜是你用来看远处的东西。
And he said Son look through this.
他说儿子看看这个。
And I did.
我做到了。
And I saw a little blue orange disk and I couldn't believe that with my own eyes I could see another
我看到了一个蓝色的橙色小圆盘，我不敢相信我能亲眼看到另一个
planet.
行星。
I could even see little little lines on the surface of the planet.
我什至可以看到地球表面的细小线条。
And from that point I've been fascinated by Mars had been fascinated by the idea of going there.
从那时起，我就对火星很着迷，对去那里的想法也很着迷。
Do you care already.
你已经在乎了吗。
Do you feel like wow I could be interested in Mars now because it's kind of happening through me right
你觉得哇，我现在可能对火星感兴趣，因为它是通过我发生的，对吗？
now.
现在。
One reason is because humans are naturally interested in stories but the other is because because of
一个原因是因为人类天生对故事感兴趣，但另一个原因是因为
empathy here are some other ways we could we could begin.
移情这里是我们可以开始的一些其他方式。
Let me tell you.
让我告诉你。
Let me tell you about how I first got involved with finance finance is a very boring field so maybe
让我告诉你我是如何开始接触金融的 金融是一个非常无聊的领域，所以也许
I'm going to talk about finance and I tell you a little story about how I first got interested in this
我要谈谈金融，我告诉你一个小故事，关于我最初是如何对这个感兴趣的
and why it's important to me this field about money.
以及为什么这个关于金钱的领域对我很重要。
Some people some people think it's boring.
有些人有些人认为这很无聊。
Some people think it's interesting.
有些人认为这很有趣。
I think it can be interesting.
我认为这可能很有趣。
But if we first care about the story then we'll maybe start caring about finance maybe maybe about three
但如果我们首先关心这个故事，那么我们可能会开始关心金融，也许大约三个
years ago I went I went on a trip to Ethiopia and on that trip blah blah blah something happened.
几年前，我去埃塞俄比亚旅行，在那次旅行中发生了一些事情。
And that's the thing that maybe got me started on this big project that I'm doing whatever it happens
这可能是让我开始这个大项目的原因，我正在做任何事情发生
to be.
成为。
OK.
好的。
So I start a little story.
所以我开始一个小故事。
This is a great way to connect with your audience.
这是与观众建立联系的好方法。
This is type 2.
这是类型 2。
When it comes to making hooks.
说到制作钩子。
Now let's go on and talk about the last type of hook.
现在让我们继续讨论最后一种类型的钩子。
So the last type of hook is also a way to interact with the audience.
所以最后一种钩子也是一种与观众互动的方式。
And I want to sort of connect these two points together.
我想将这两点连接在一起。
I said I was going to talk about how you could interact with the audience and one way to do that is
我说我要谈谈你如何与观众互动，一种方法是
also a way to do a hook.
也是一种钩子的方法。
This is to get a show of hands.
这是为了举手。
This is a little bit of what we would call audience participation.
这就是我们所说的观众参与的一点点。
Audience Power Dissipation you want to get the audience to do something.
Audience Power Dissipation 你想让观众做某事。
And by doing that by getting them to do something they're now part of your presentation.
通过让他们做某事来做到这一点，他们现在是您演示文稿的一部分。
They're now with you.
他们现在和你在一起。
They're a piece of it.
他们是其中的一部分。
Before it was just you standing up there giving the presentation.
之前只有你站在那里进行演示。
Now it's you and them together in a way because they've done something to contribute to it and they
现在是你和他们在某种程度上在一起，因为他们已经做了一些事情来为它做出贡献，他们
feel now a little bit maybe a little bit responsible for it.
现在觉得有点可能对它有点负责。
Oh I'm part of this thing.
哦，我是这件事的一部分。
So how can we get people to put their hands up.
那么我们怎样才能让人们举手。
Well we can just say hands up after a question for example who here doesn't own a smartphone.
好吧，我们可以在一个问题之后说举手，例如这里谁没有智能手机。
Hands up hands.
举手。
Who doesn't own a smartphone.
谁没有智能手机。
This is not rhetorical.
这不是修辞。
This is a real question.
这是一个真正的问题。
But I want the person who doesn't have one to put their hand up.
但我希望没有的人举手。
And so maybe I don't know if it's an audience of 200 people one or two people might not have a smartphone
所以也许我不知道它是否有 200 人的观众一两个人可能没有智能手机
maybe.
也许。
So two people put their hands up and I say you should always say something about the result because
所以两个人举手，我说你应该总是对结果说些什么，因为
you have the best perspective or view of the audience.
你有观众的最佳视角或观点。
I mean that physically I mean physically from where you're standing you can see the audience better
我的意思是身体上我的意思是身体上从你站的地方你可以更好地看到观众
than anyone else.
比谁都。
So you have the best perspective.
所以你有最好的观点。
OK.
好的。
So we could say just by show of hands who here doesn't have a smartphone.
所以我们可以通过举手来判断这里没有智能手机的人。
Two people put their hands up.
两个人举手。
Oh that's what I thought.
哦，我就是这么想的。
That's what I thought to people about to.
这就是我对人们的想法。
So my guess was about right.
所以我的猜测是正确的。
I guessed most people would not put their hands up because most people have a smartphone.
我猜大多数人不会举手，因为大多数人都有智能手机。
OK.
好的。
So you should report the results if it's about 50 percent you can say OK about about half of you half
所以你应该报告结果如果大约 50% 你可以说 OK 大约一半的人
of you about half of you don't.
你们中大约一半的人没有。
OK just by a show of hands.
只需举手即可。
This is another expression just by a show of hands who here I know that doesn't look like it but that's
这是举手的另一种表达方式，我知道这里看起来不像，但那是
an R there who here would like to live to be more than 100 who here would like to live to be more than
那里的 R 在这里想活到 100 岁以上 谁在这里想活到 100 岁以上
a hundred.
一百。178
Oh wow.
哇哦。
OK.
好的。
About a third of you would like to live to be more than 100.
大约三分之一的人希望活到 100 岁以上。
So we can judge the results a little bit.
所以我们可以稍微判断一下结果。
Give everybody a feeling for their level of participation and then go on and talk about the actual thing
让每个人感受一下他们的参与程度，然后继续谈论实际的事情
whatever it is we're going to talk about.
不管我们要谈的是什么。
So these are the three types of hooks that I think are the most useful and probably are the most common.
所以这是我认为最有用并且可能是最常见的三种类型的钩子。
Making it personal.
使其个性化。
Asking for a show of hands and asking a rhetorical question if you know how to use these well you can
要求举手并提出反问，如果你知道如何使用这些，你可以
always get your presentation.
总是得到你的介绍。
Started off the right way.
以正确的方式开始。